Guide to the OutServe-SLDN Records, 1993-2013.
OutServe-SLDN Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
OutServe-SLDN Records, 1993-2013.
7821
OutServe-SLDN
20
Organizational records, printed materials, legal documents, CDs, DVDs, and Videos.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pamphlets provided to soldiers, videos and photos of national dinners organized to support the repeal of Don't Ask Don't Tell, and other posters and records of the organization.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Since 1993, OutServe-Servicemembers Legal Defense Network (SLDN) has represented the United States Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual and Transgender (LGBT) community worldwide. OutServe-SLDN is a non-partisan, non-profit (501-c-3), legal services, watchdog and policy organization that provides free and direct legal assistance to service members and veterans affected by the repealed "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" (DADT) law, the current ban on open authentic transgender service and those currently serving who may experience harassment or discrimination. OutServe-SLDN is the heir to the legacy of providing legal services to service members and veterans. From representing over 12,000 service members during the era of DADT to leading the fight to repeal DADT, OutServe-SLDN has been on the frontlines for over 20 years and currently has over 75,000 followers worldwide and over 7,000 active members serving and leading more than 80 chapters around the globe.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Pamphlets provided to soldiers, videos and photos of national dinners organized to support the repeal of DADT, and other posters and records of the organization and its efforts to repeal the Don't Ask Don't Tell policy.
SUBJECTS
Names:
OutServe-SLDN; OutServe; OutServe-SLDN
Subjects:
United States -- Armed Forces; Veterans; Transgender military personnel; Gay military personnel; Don't Ask, Don't Tell policy; Homosexuality; Sexual orientation
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Also see Chai Feldblum papers, #7697.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Case Files
Series II. Applicable Regulations & Directives
Series III. Research, Official Reports, and SLDN Administrative Files
Series IV. Media, Posters and Awards
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Case Files
  - A Proposal from the Campaign for Military Service to the Senate Hearings on Lifting the Ban on Gays and Lesbians in the Armed Forces: Proposed Witnesses for Nunn Framework Phase I, March 29-31, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Testimonials Anonymous (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - History and Legal overview (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Issues, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Record, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
  - SECDEF memorandum to Service Secretaries, et al., 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Supreme Court, October Term, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Watson v. United States, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - History and Legal overview, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
  - International Comparisons, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Issue and Witness Briefing Book, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Rev. Dusty Pruitt v. Secretary of Defense; Secretary of the Army; Ronald W. Zeltman, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Margarethe Cammermeyer v. Les Aspin et al., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Joseph Steffan appeal, three volumes, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Lackland, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Steffan pamphlets (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Newak, 1987, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fair v. Rumsfeld (Box 2, Folder 5-8)
  - Re: Amendment 2 Decision: Colorado Supreme Court (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Thomasson, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
  - Fair v. Rumsfeld, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Witt - Brief, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - US v. Harvey - Brief, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pietrangelo, II (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Ready Reference Binder: "The Battle Book" (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Edwin J. Christian (Box 3, Folder 10-15)
- Series II. Applicable Regulations & Directives
  - HQ ARPC/JA Guide to Inquiry Officers (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - United States Marine Corps Personnel Policies (Box 4, Folder 1)
    1 Folder: Note on binder reads "Spencer First Project"
  - Separation Procedures (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Military HIV/TDRL Regulations (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Separation Pay for Involuntary Discharge & the Administrative Procedure Act, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
  - Separation Pay (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - ARMY Regulations Vol. 1 (Box 4, Folder 8-10)
  - ARMY Regulations Vol. 2 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - ARMY Regulations Vol. 3 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - ARMY Regulations Vol. 4 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Coast Guard Regulations, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Coast Guard Regulations (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - NAVY, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5-6)
  - JAGMAN (NAVY), 2004 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Training: UCMJ: NAVY, Marine Corps, Air Force, General Department of Defense Policy, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Harassment Training Materials: NAVY, Marine Corps, Coast Guard (Box 5, Folder 11-12)
  - Harassment Training Materials: Department of Defense, ARMY, Air Force (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Air Force Regulations (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Air Force: Regulations AFI Personnel (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Marine Corps Policy, NAVY Policy: Personnel Policies, 2000-2002 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Marine Corps Regulations, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Department of Defense Directives, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
- Series III. Research, Official Reports, and SLDN Administrative Files
  - General Research and Reports
    - Recoupment, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Retirement in Lieu of Separation: Research & Regulations (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
    - Evaluation Report: "Sexual Orientation and U.S. Military Personnel Policy: Options and Assessment" by National Defense Research Institute, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      Published Report
    - Evaluation Report: Military Environment with Respect to the Homosexual Conduct policy, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Background Information on Homosexuals in the Military, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Planning for Diversity: Options and Recommendations for DoD Leaders, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Dev(out): Responding to Anti-Gay Religion by (Out)Giving (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence re: Policy Concerning Homosexuality in the Armed Forces, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Old Photographs: Oral History Forms and Photographs (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Military Chaplains Outreach Correspondence, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Contains CD titled "Voter Breakdown Target States: SLDN 2003"
    - RAND Report: Executive Summary (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Found in Evaluation Report "Sexual Orientation and U.S. Military Personnel Policy"
    - Crittendon Report: Report of the Board Appointed to Prepare and Submit Recommendations to the Secretary of the NAVY for the Revision of Policies, Procedures and Directives Dealing with Homosexuals published, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Research Papers Regarding Homosexuals in the United States Military (Box 7, Folder 14-15)
    - General Accounting Office (GOA) Reports (Box 7, Folder 16-17)
    - A New Beginning: Policy Recommendations to Improve the Lives of LGBT People and Eliminate Discrimination from Federal Policies (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - General Accounting Office (GAO) Research, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - Report of the Comprehensive Review of the Issues Associated with a Repeal of "Don't Ask, Don't Tell", November 30, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Center for the Study of Sexual Minorities in the Military Materials (CSSMM) and Materials on Gays in Foreign Militaries (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
    - Research regarding "Don't Ask, Don't Tell", 2003-2007 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The National Lawyers Guild Military Task Force: HIV policies, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - RAND Report, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Don't Ask, Don't Tell" materials, SLDN, 1996-2009 (Box 8, Folder 10-11)
    - Background Materials on "Don’t Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Pursue", 1999 (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
    - Background Materials on "Don’t Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Pursue, Don't Harass" (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - HASC Testimony and Prep, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Don't Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Be", by Alexander Raggio (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Law Review Articles (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - SLDN conference materials, articles, and newsletters (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - SLDN conference materials, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Campaign for Military Service publications, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - SLDN Survival Guide, 2007 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Defense Force Management Statistics, 1992, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Secretary of the Army's Senior Review Panel Report on Sexual Harassment, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Legal Publications (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Legal Background Documents (Box 21)
      Various Legal Reports
  - SLDN Training Materials and Administrative Files
    - Servicemembers Legal Defense Network Military Advisory Council minutes, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - SLDN: Day-to-Day Operations Manual (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - SLDN: Staff Attorney Training Materials (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - SLDN: Plan Giving Requests (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - SLDN: Employee Handbook (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - SLDN: Legislative Support Binder (Background Materials on "Don't Ask, Don't Tell") (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Communications manual and protocol (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Truman Project Partners: Orientation by Truman National Security Project, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - SLDN: Policies and Fundraising (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - SLDN budget reports, direct mail, administrative material, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Hate Message protocol (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Hate mail, emails, and letters (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Gay Discharge Numbers and Conduct Unbecoming Reports
    - Gay Discharge Numbers, 1980 - 1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gay Discharge Numbers, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Gay Discharge Numbers, 1999-2004 (Box 9, Folder 8-13)
    - Separations Due to Homosexual Conduct, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - National Guard and Reserve Unites Called to Active Duty by Branch, 1998-2003 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Freedom of Information Act Requests for Discharge Numbers (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
    - Conduct Unbecoming Annual Reports: "Don't Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Pursue, Don't Harass", 1997-2004 (Box 10, Folder 5-6)
    - Conduct Unbecoming Annual Reports: "Don't Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Pursue, Don't Harass", spiral bound official publications, 1996-2004 (Box 10)
- Series IV. Media, Posters and Awards
  - Betacam
    - Vince Patton III USCG-MCPOCG, V-9090-9091 (Box 12)
    - Vince Patton III, Dr. Cook, V-9092 (Box 12)
    - Fr. John Cook and Lara Ballard, V-9093 (Box 12)
    - Lara Ballard, V-9094 (Box 12)
    - Denise Ligget and Lauren Brown, V-9095 (Box 12)
    - Lauren Brown and Pat and Wally Kuteles, V-9096 (Box 12)
    - Pat and Willy Kuteles and Frank Kameny, V-9097 (Box 12)
    - Frank Kameny, V-9098 (Box 12)
    - Eric Andersen, V-9099 (Box 12)
    - Andre Taylor, V-9100 (Box 12)
    - Andre Taylor and Alistare Gamble, V-9101 (Box 12)
    - Alistare Gamble, V-9102 (Box 12)
    - SLDN Presentations, 2004; V-9103-9104 (Box 12)
    - Unlabelled, V-9105-9106, 9113 (Box 12)
    - SLDN 12 Annual End the Witch Hunts Dinner, 2004; V-9107-9108 (Box 12)
    - Nightline "Don't Ask, Don't Tell", 1996; V-9109 (Box 12)
    - SLDN Dinner, Washington DC, 2002; V-9110 (Box 12)
    - SLDN Dinner, 2002; V-9111 (Box 12)
    - SLDN JAG school training, 2002; V-9112 (Box 12)
    - Lauren Brown, V-9114 (Box 12)
  - VHS
    - Coming Out Under Fire, 1995; V-9115 (Box 15)
    - Lifetime "Any Mother's Son", V-9116 (Box 12)
    - SLDN Presentation, 2004; V-9117 (Box 12)
    - Soldier's Girl, V-9118, 9120-9121 (Box 15)
    - The Question of Equality, V-9119 (Box 12)
    - "I am a Homosexual", V-9122 (Box 15)
    - To Support and Defend, V-9123 (Box 15)
    - Soldier's Girl, V-9124 (Box 15)
    - Coming out Under Fire, V-9125-9126 (Box 15)
    - Open Secrets, V-9127 (Box 12)
    - SLDN Presentations, 2004; V-9128 (Box 15)
    - SLDN ETWH, V-9129 (Box 15)
    - "Signing Up: It's your choice, V-9130 (Box 15)
    - Dream Out Loud, V-9131 (Box 15)
    - MTV's Real World 9: New Orleans, V-9132 (Box 15)
    - Don't Ask Don't Tell, 2004; V-9133 (Box 15)
  - Cassettes
    - Don't Ask, Don't Tell, Don't Believe, tr-10880 (Box 15)
    - Plenary Three: Dr. Mel White, 1994; tr-10881 (Box 15)
    - Beyond Don't Ask Don't Tell, 1994; tr-10882 (Box 15)
    - The Kennedy Years: An Anthology, tr-10883 (Box 15)
    - A Love Worth Fighting For, tr-10884 (Box 15)
    - Gays in the Military, tr-10885 (Box 15)
    - Out this Week, 1995; tr-10886 (Box 15)
    - The Broadcast Edition of the Christian Science Monitor, tr-10887 (Box 15)
  - Awards and Artwork
    - Walkjer Award GLBT Historical Society for Service to Country and Community, 2007 (Box 13)
    - SLDN San Francisco Proclamation, 1995 (Box 13)
    - Political cartoon drawing (Box 13)
    - Kansas City Star news clipping regarding parents of soldier killed in barracks, 2004-10-02 (Box 13)
    - SLDN "Lift the Ban" Donation container, MU-1928 (Box 14)
    - Artwork and posters (Folder 1-3)
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books - cataloged individually in the Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections
Boushka, Bill Our Fundamental Rights And How We Can Reclaim Them: A Psychological Approach, 1998
Carey, John J., Editor The Christian Argument for Gays and Lesbians in the Military, 1993
Coye, Beth F. My Navy Too, 1998 (signed)
Drenner, Karla and Paul Clere One: A True Story of Politics, Prayer, and the Power of One, 2002
Dyer, Kate, Editor Gays in Uniform: The Pentagon's Secret Reports, 1990
Humphrey, Mary Ann My Country, My Right To Serve,1990
Johnson, William Stacy A Time to Embrace, 2006
Kennedy, Claudia J. and Malcolm McConnell Generally Speaking: A Memoir By The First Woman Promoted To Three-Star General In the United States Army, 2001
Ludmer, Christopher Trail of the Giant, 2004
Mohr, Richard D. A More Perfect Union: Why Straight America Must Stand Up For Gay Rights, 1994
People For The American Way Foundation Hostile Climate: Report on Anti-Gay Activity, 1999
People For The American Way Foundation Hostile Climate: Report on Anti-Gay Activity, 1998
Swann, Thomas A. The Tom Swann Story: For A Greater Good, 2003
Webber, Winni S. Lesbians in the Military Speak Out, 1993
Women's Research and Education Institute Women in the Military, Fourth Edition: Where They Stand, 2003
Dickinson Law Review ,Volume 102, Number 3, Spring 1998
Duke Journal of Gender Law & Policy, Volume 14, Issue 2, May 2007
The Georgetown Journal of Gender and the Law, Volume 2, Number 1, Fall 2000
The Georgetown Journal of Gender and the Law, Volume 3, Number 1, Fall 2001
The Georgetown Journal of Gender and the Law, Volume 2, Number 3, Summer 2001
Hastings Constitutional Law Quarterly, Volume 28, Number 2, Winter 2001
Hofstra Labor & Employment Law Journal, Volume 21, Number 2, Spring 2004
International Security, Volume 23, Number 2, Fall 1998
Journal of Gay, Lesbian and Bisexual Identity, Volume 3, Number 4, October 1998
New York University Law Review, Volume 70, Number 1, April 1995
Notre Dame Journal of Law, Ethics, and Public Policy, Volume 9, Number 1, 1995
UMKC Law Review, Volume 64, Number 1, Fall 1995